IGOR CAETANO DINIZ

Data Scientist, Mathematician and Manager, with 3+ years experience in python, and really strong background in mathematics and management. I've been working with Data Exploratory Analysis, machine learning models and strategy in decision making, since 2015. Furthermore, I'm finishing my Master Degree in Computational Mathematical Modelling, specialized in Machine Learning.



CONTACT

caetano_@live.com

+55 38 98863 6216

Minas Gerais - Brazil

@igorconsulting

in Igor Caetano Diniz

SKILLS

Programming

Python SOL

DAX

M Language

Methodolies

Scrum and Agile

Kaizen

Lean 6 Sigma

Software & Tools

Python Data Visualization

(Matplotlib, Seaborn)

Data handling/analysis

(numpy, scipy, pandas)

PySpark

(Real-Time, Large-Scale Data Processing)

Income and an

Jupyter Power BI

(BI and Visualization, KPIs Management)

Trello

(Routine Management)

Office

(Good presentations)

Machine Learning & Al

Supervised Learning

(Regression, Classification)

Unsupervised Learning

(e. g. Clustering) Clouds

IBM Cloud

AWS

Languages

English

Spanish



CERTIFICATES

- IBM Data Scientist
- DataCamp Data Science in Python and Data Analysis in Python & SQL Certificates

WORK HISTORY

01/2022 - present

Smart House Construções - MG Manager and Data Analyst

- Manage the Debt Recovery Sector, implementing lean 6 sigma, Business Intelligence and Data Science to achieve goals established after analysis and continuous improvement. Leadership and management of a multitasking and high performance team, with decision making in different areas, from people management to sector strategy

1 02/2015 - 12/2017

Q Hangar - RJ

Manager and Consultant

- Manage team of colaborators, train they in technology expertise like programming, Data Analysis, Robotics using Arduino and how to transform ideas into a scalable product and generate value with results

12/2015 - 12/2017

♀ IME - RJ

Data Analyst in Computer Eng

- I worked on creating of anti-cheat typing pattern recognizer using SQL to standardized, clean e manipulation of data and Python to verify the identity using machine learning methods, like deep learning with some algorithms to train and recognize.

EDUCATION

1 01/2021 - 03/2023

PUC-Rio, Rio de Janeiro. Brazil

Master Degree

Mathematical Modelling and Optimization - Machine Learning Methods in Oil and Gas Industry. Petrobras Project

1 01/2018 - 12/2020

PUC-Rio, Rio de Janeiro. Brazil

Bachelor in Mathematics

1 01/2015 - 12/2017

♀ IME, Rio de Janeiro. Brazil

Bachelor in Telecom. Engineering

Typing pattern recognition - anti-fraud distance learning project using Machine Learning

ACHIEVEMENTS, HONOURS AND AWARDS

- Master Degree in Mathematics Mathematical Modelling and Optimization Especial Student for Excellence
- Bachelor in Mathematics 1st Place Score 9.0 and Scholarship for Academic Excellence

GENERAL SKILLS

Data Science Data Analysis Machine Learning Supervised Learning Unsupervised Learning Data Visualization Python Management Scrum Agile Continuous Improvement Lean6Sigma

MOST RECENT PROJECTS

DATA PROJECTS

Financial and Customer Services - Neon and Massula Consulting

Creation of a data pipeline, from data extraction to visualization in sectors from Customer Service to Finance. In particular, in the financial area, data analysis workflows, the balance sheet, in which a more effective delivery of results was observed and forecasting unexpected expenses related to interest and unplanned services. Data Warehouse and ETL process standardization, Exploratory analysis and Data Visualization via Power BI, Excel and SQL Smart House Buildings

Standardization of the entire Management process, from the creation of Data Warehouse, ETL processes, exploratory analysis and data visualization processes, to the standardization of decision-making, related to the debt recovery sector as a strategic sector. This process brought a reduction of more than 50% of indebted customers, going from around 1200 customers to less than 600, and a recovery of almost 1 million reais from profit.

Debt forecast project - Smart House Buildings

After recovery, the next project was to forecast total losses. Using logistic regression algorithm, and validating it, the objective of the project was to predict customers who would always be debtors. From this, my decision-making was facilitated as a manager of the sector to refer such cases to the legal sector, guaranteeing the integrity of the profit of such ventures.